Pandas is a powerful tool for data analysis and manipulation.
Pandas 是强大的数据分析和处理工具
If you remember from the last lesson,
如果你还记得上一节课的内容
this package is built on top of NumPy which makes it very fast and efficient.
你就知道这个包是建立在 NumPy 之上的 因而十分快捷高效
In this lesson, we will go over the two main data structures in Pandas.
本课将介绍 Pandas 的两种主要数据结构
The Pandas series and the Panda's dataframe.
Pandas 序列和 Pandas DataFrame
Let's start off by learning about the Pandas series object, and how to create one.
我们先来讲 Pandas 序列对象及其创建方式
When importing Pandas, use a standard alias, pd.
用标准别名 pd 导入 Pandas
Let's create a series containing grocery items.
我们来创建一个有关杂货的序列 groceries
To access the series object,
要访问序列对象
we just type pd.Series with a capital S.
只需输入 pd.Series 注意 S 大写
A panda series is a one-dimensional array-like object that can hold many data types,
Pandas 序列是种一维类数组对象 可以存放许多数据类型
such as numbers and strings.
比如数字和字符串
This is different from a NumPy array which can only hold one data type.
这与 NumPy 数组不同 后者只能存放一种数据类型
Another big difference between a Pandas series and
Pandas 序列和 NumPy 数组另一个明显区别在于
a NumPy array is that you can assign an index label to each element in the Pandas series.
你可以给 Pandas 序列的各元素赋上索引标签
Here, we pass two arguments,
这里要输入两个参数
the data and the indices.
数据和索引
For our grocery series and we will use food names as
在序列 groceries 里 我们用食物名作为索引标签
index labels and the quantities we need to buy as our data.
用要购入的数量作为数据
We can see that a Pandas series is displayed with the indices in the first column,
可以看到 Pandas 序列的第一列是索引
and the data in the second column.
第二列是数据
Notice that the data is not indexed zero to three,
注意 这里的数据索引不是从 0 到 3
but rather with the names of the foods that we put in,
而是我们输入的食物名
eggs, apples, milk, and bread.
eggs (鸡蛋)、apples (苹果)、milk (牛奶) 和 bread (面包)
Also notice that the data in our Pandas series has both integers and strings,
还要注意 这个 Pandas 序列的数据既有整数也有字符串
just like NumPy arrays.
和 NumPy 数组一样
Pandas series have attributes that allow us to get
Pandas 序列也有一些属性
information from them in an easy way. Let's see some of them.
方便我们从中获取信息 我们来具体探讨下
Shape gives us the sizes of each dimension of the data,
shape 表示数据各维度的大小
ndim gives us the number of dimensions of the data,
ndim 表示数据的维数
and size gives us the total number of values in the array.
size 表示数组里总共有多少个值
We can also print the index labels and the data of the Pandas series separately.
我们也可以分别输出 Pandas 序列的索引标签和数据
This is useful if you don't happen to know what the index labels of a series are.
如果你不知道序列的索引标签 这个功能就显得十分实用了
This gives us the index labels of the series object,
这里给出了序列对象的索引标签
and this gives us the data into series object.
这里给出了序列对象的数据
If you're dealing with a very large Pandas series,
如果你处理的 Pandas 序列十分庞大
and you're unsure whether an index label exists,
你又不确定序列是否有某个索引标签
you can always check using the In command.
那你可以用 in 命令来确认
This let's us know that bananas is not one of the index labels in the grocery series,
这样操作 就可以知道 banana (香蕉) 不是序列 groceries 的索引标签了
and this tells us that bread is.
这里则告诉我们 bread (面包) 是序列的索引标签